Guide to the Consumer Reports. Esther Peterson papers, 1953-1997 and undated RL.11791
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Print Materials, 1978-1993 and undated; 7
  - American Friends Service Committee: "The Global Factory", 1990 (Box 17)
  - Center for Post-Soviet Studies--Perspectives on Change conference proceedings, 1993 (Box 17)
  - Centre for Our Common Future--Global Forum '94, 1994 (Box 17)
  - CEP (Council on Economic Priorities)--Shopping for a Better World, 1990 (Box 17)
  - Citizen Advocacy News (AARP), 1992 (Box 17)
  - Cleared for Export: An Examination of the European Communities' Pharmaceutical and Chemical Trade (in English and Spanish), 1985 (Box 17)
    Copies in English and Spanish.
  - Codex Alimentarius--Procedural Manual, 7th Ed., 1989 (Box 17)
  - Congressional Hearing--Status of UN Code of Conduct on Transnational Corporations, 1989 (Box 17)
  - Consolidated List of Products Whose Consumption and/or Sale Have Been Banned, Withdrawn, Severely Restricted, or Not Approved by Governments, 1984, 1991; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Consumer Interpol, 1989-1990 (Box 17)
  - Consumer Protection for Latin America and the Caribbean, 1987 (Box 17)
  - Consumer Rights from Now On: Moving Toward the Creation of the UN Guidelines for Consumer Protection, 1987 (Box 17)
    Material in Japanese; features images of Peterson; includes sheet with table of contents in English
  - Drug Labeling in Developing Countries, 1993 (Box 17)
  - Hazardous Substances Export Policy--A Documentary Collection, 1983 (Box 17)
  - IBFAN (International Baby Food Action Network)--"Breaking the Rules", 1991 (Box 17)
  - Insurance consumer education materials, 1980-1989 (Box 17)
    Includes material from Kemper Insurance, Allstate, the National Consumers League, U.S. General Services Administration, Massachusetts Division of Insurance, and the Insurance Information Institute
  - IOCU--Affiliate newsletters, 1989-1993 (Box 18)
    A few issues from El Ojo del Consumidor, Consumers Union of Japan, and Atut (Polish consumer organization). Material in Polish and Spanish.
  - IOCU--Annual Reports, 1981-1991 (Box 18)
  - IOCU--Asia/Pacific Regional Office publications, 1983 (Box 18)
  - IOCU--Comments on the UN Draft Guidelines for Consumer Protection, 1983 (Box 18)
  - IOCU--Consumer Currents, 1988-1990 (Box 17)
  - IOCU--Consumers and Development, 1989 (Box 17)
  - IOCU--Consumers and the Environment, 1992 (Box 17)
  - IOCU--Consumers in Africa, 1988 (Box 17)
  - IOCU--Health, Safety, and the Consumer, 1983 (Box 17)
  - IOCU--Knowledge is Power, 1970 (Box 17)
  - IOCU--Newsletters, 1987-1993 (Box 18)
  - IOCU--Pamphlets and brochures, 1984 (Box 18)
    Includes IOCU Newsletter, scattered issues of: World Consumer, The Consumer Protector
  - IOCU--Publications, 1982-1990 (Box 18)
  - IOCU--SIS Newsletter, 1989-1990 (Box 18)
    General IOCU information pamphlets, Report on the seminar on Appropriate Products (1982), "International Law and the Consumer Interest," "5 billion consumers: organizing for change" (in English and Spanish)
  - IOCU--The CEN-ter Folder: Collection, 1985-1987--Resource Material for Consumer Educators (Box 18)
  - IOCU--Violating the Pesticide Code--A Survey of Indonesia, the Philippines, and Thailand, 1987 (Box 18)
  - IOCU--World Consumer Rights Day, 1992 (Box 18)
  - Labor Newsletters--ICFTU and ILO, 1993 (Box 18)
  - Latin American and Caribbean Women's Health Network, 1989-1990; 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Magazines, 1989-1993 (Box 18)
    Includes 1 issue each of: World Watch, Presidents and Prime Ministers, SASH: Focus on Corruption
  - Multinational Monitor, 1987-1993 (Box 18)
  - National Underwriter, 1989 (Box 18)
  - Non-Governmental Liaison Service, 1993 (Box 18)
  - Other consumer organizations' newsletters, 1989-1990 (Box 18)
    Publications include: ACCI Newsletter, Consumer Affairs Letter, CFA News, Consumers Union News Digest, HAI File, International Barometer, NCL Bulletin, Public Citizen
  - Pesticides--Brochures, advertisements, approximately 1984 (Box 18)
  - Pharmaceutical pamphlets (PMA, IFPMA), 1981-1985 (Box 18)
    Pharmaceutical Manufacturers' Association, International Federation of Pharmaceutical Manufacturers and Associations
  - PIA--Auto and homeowners insurance pamphlets, approximately 1989 (Box 18)
  - Promotional material (Information Services), 1990 (Box 18)
  - Restless, Esther Peterson (memoir), 1995 (Box 18)
  - Society for International Development publications, 1993 (Box 18)
  - Test Case: Pineapples, 1987 (Box 18)
  - The UN and How it Works; UN Charter, 1962 (Box 18)
  - Transnational Corporations Research Project, 1984 (Box 18)
  - Transnationals, 1989 (Box 18)
  - UNA/USA publications, 1988-1993 (Box 18)
    Includes a few issues of The Interdependent.
  - UN--Consumer Protection: A Resource Handbook, 1990 (Box 18)
  - UNCTC bibliography, Current Studies, CTC Reporter, 1986-1990 (Box 18)
  - UNCTC reports and public hearings, 1983-1992 (Box 18)
  - UNDP--Creating a Better Climate for Private Enterprise, 1987 (Box 18)
  - UN--Essential Drugs Monitor, 1993 (Box 18)
  - UN--Guidelines for Consumer Protection, 1986 (Box 18)
  - UNHCR--Refugees, 1993 (Box 18)
  - UN--Pamphlets and brochures, 1984-1993 (Box 18)
  - UN--Permanent Mission to the United Nations, No. 264, 1989 Mar. (Box 18)
  - Warning: Reaganomics is still harmful to consumers (National Consumers League), 1983 (Box 18)
  - What I Have Learned About Life Insurance, 1934 (Box 18)
  - WHO--International Code of Marketing of Breast-Milk Substitutes, 1981 (Box 18)
  - Women's Publications (UNIFEM, IWRAW), 1993-1994 (Box 18)
  - World Bank Publications Update, 1993 (Box 18)
  - World Citizen News, 1993 (Box 18)
  - World Federalist, 1993 (Box 18)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1989; 8
  - NAPSLO (National Association of Professional Surplus Lines Offices) panel, 1989 Sept. 22 (Box 4, Audio-cassette RL11791-CS-001)
    Participants include: Esther Peterson, Robert Hunter, John Crosby, Donald Green.